Kimberly Michelle Patel

(m) 801-915-7957 kimmbie@gmail.com

Personal Bio:

Passionate about Web Development and Design. In 2017 I was asked to create a Patient Resource Website for a private physician. This was created through Adobe Muse and I am excited to be able to re-create this site for the medical population using proper HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Experienced medical claims adjudicator with 20+ years of experience in the medical field. Certified as a National Pharmacy Technician I believe will assist clients whom deal with sensitive medical data. Understudy in all aspects of short film media production. Graduated from University of Utah with Bachelor of Science and a minor in Criminology. Additional pre-med education through Salt Lake Community College.

Certification:

•	2017	National Pharmacy Technician License # 9788374-1717
•	2017	National Healthcare Association Certification #S20312C3

Education and Training:

•	2018	Developer Challenge Scholarship 4 month	Udacity Google
•	2017	Pharmacy Technician	Pharmacy Technician University
•	2015	Leadership Development II- Psy7	PSI Success Course
•	2007	Self Defense Trainer	PCS Grand Master Tom Garriga
•	2004	Pre-Med/Health Science	Salt Lake Community College
•	2000	B.S. Sociology/Criminology	University of Utah

Volunteer:

- 2017 Facebook Marketing Pediatric Liver Transplant Utah
 - Developed a Nonprofit Organization Facebook page for the Pediatric Liver Transplant Program for Primary Children's/University of Utah. This page serves as a non-HIPAA format for communicating public information regarding the program including fundraisers, support groups and media events.
- 2017 Website www.pedsgi.net Dr. R.A. Patel
 - This webpage was built on Adobe Muse and is a patient and family resource page on common pediatric gastroenterology conditions. Currently it serves as the most direct way to provide information for Dr. R.A. Patel, an academic Pediatric Gastroenterologist serving the Salt Lake County area.
- 2016 Media/Film Production & Video Editing Toy Shed Production Studio's
 - Participated in all aspects of studio production: writing, setup, set design, lighting, initial film editing with Adobe Premiere Pro, auditioning and arranging talent for short comedic skits etc.

Professional Experience:

- Home Infusion RX Medical Claims Adjuster University of Utah
 2013 to 2018
 - Review physician orders, discharge notes and pharmacist dispense to ensure proper billing of home infusion medical claims in accordance with variety of insurance company contract
 - o Ensure timely receipt of revenue approximately \$2-3 million per month
 - Coordinate with patients for co-payment or co-payment assistance
- Insurance Claims Adjuster
 Workers Compensation Fund
 2012-2013
 - o Interview injured workers, employees and witnesses to determine liability
 - Investigate inconsistencies and order appropriate testing
 - o Claims management, litigation and referral to appropriate resources
 - Marketing additional services provided by WCF fund to business owners
 - Deliver verbal and written information to healthcare workers, employers and employees regarding case findings and resolution
 - Sr. Disability Examiner/Adjudicator Social Security Administration 2002-2012
 - Evaluate medical records and vocational factors
 - Prepare educated written assessment of the claimant's residual functioning capacity as it related to disability as defined by the SSA
 - Present written and verbal assessment of the evidence to the Physicians' and Psychologists' on staff for final approval of my determination
 - Maintain a high level of accuracy and quality (97% average over 10 years)
 - o Independent caseload management working claims
 - o Interpretation of technical information found within policy and procedure
 - Sr. Employment Counselor
- Department of Workforce Services 2000-2002
- Counsel individuals requiring financial and training assistance from the State of Utah.
- o Interview individuals to determine appropriate referral and usage of Federal funds
- Tracked and monitored all training services for clientele ensuring performance standard expectations and expenditures maintained within budget
- Managed 60+ individuals monthly receiving said service

Technical Skills:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- PHP
- WordPress
- Epic Systems Healthcare EMR
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Muse (no longer used)
- Adobe Premier Pro
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Excel

Portfolio & Projects:

- http://www.pedsgi.net/
- Animal Beach Postcard.psd